## **Annelise Smith**

# UX Designer

### Skills

User Research
Usability Testing
Ethnography
Personas
Wireframing
Journey Mapping
Content Analysis
Paper Prototyping
Mobile Design
Axure
Sketch
InVision
OmniGraffle
Adobe Illustrator
HTML/CSS

## Education

**UX Design Immersive**General Assembly Seattle
2016

UX Fundamentals Course
School of Visual Concepts
2015

#### MA in Human Development

Washington State University 2013

#### **BA Social Sciences**

Washington State University
Minor in Ethnic Studies
Minor in German
2011

# annelisesmithux@gmail.com bestuxdesignerever.com

## **About**

I'm a **UX designer** with a background in developmental psychology. I'm experienced at applying **user-centered methodologies** to identify core user needs and motivations. My super power is translating these insights into **evidence-based designs** that meet both user needs and business goals.

## Experience

Lead UX Designer // Dive Around the Clock // Seattle, WA // Oct 2016 - present

Improve alignment of website with user needs through primary user research including interviews, usability testing, and behavioral observation; utilize IA principles and develop site maps/wireframes that enable intuitive navigation and increase click-through to donation and volunteer registration tasks; create new visual branding.

UX Designer in Residence // General Assembly // Seattle, WA // Jan 2016 - April 2016

Teach user experience design and user interaction fundamentals in an immersive UX design course; lead information architecture, form design, and usability testing workshops; provide design critiques and feedback on mobile and web design projects; organize a campus-wide hackathon; provide student support and mentoring; oversee class logistics; update and design curriculum to align with current industry standards;

**Field Marketing Specialist** // Publicis Hawkeye // Seattle, WA // Oct 2015-Aug 2016

Devise, organize, and execute guerrilla marketing campaigns to drive product awareness and foster brand loyalty

Investigator // WA Child Protective Services // Tacoma, WA // Oct 2014- Oct 2015

Conduct in-home interviews and rapport-building to identify core family problems and make critical legal decisions under limited time constraints and in high-stress situations; facilitate creative solutions to child safety problems using existing family and community resources; create accurate documentation in compliance with federal mandates.

Site Coordinator // Communities in Schools // Lakewood, WA // Aug 2013- Oct 2014

Collaborate with student, family, school, and community stakeholders to identify core student needs and secure community-level resources for at-risk students.

Research Coordinator // WA State University // Pullman, WA // Aug 2011- Aug 2013

Create and oversee implementation of data collection/analysis timeline; develop outcome evaluation plans for existing health promotion programs; design, implement, and evaluate social media health campaigns; collaborate on scholarly publications; write research briefs and literature reviews to support evidence-based decision making.